# Justin Focus

https://github.com/justinline | Github iamjustinfocus@gmail.com | 07479 338 238

# **EDUCATION**

### **UWE**

BA IN FASHION DESIGN AND COMMUNICATION 2009-2013 | Bristol, UK

# **BOURNVILLE COLLEGE**

3D DESIGN

2008-2009 | Bournville, Uk Foundation Degree

#### KING EDWARDS VI COLLEGE

4 A LEVELS:

2006-2008 | Stourbridge, UK Biology, Chemistry, Computing, Psychology

# LINKS

Github:// justinline LinkedIn:// Justin Focus Codewars:// justinline

# SKILLS

# **DEVELOPMENT**

Familiarity with:

Django (+ REST) • Python • JS • HTML5 CSS3 • Bootstrap • SASS • Angular1 PHP • JSON/XML • MySQL|PostreSQL LAMP • Linux • Terminal • git • Bootstrap

Learning:
C • C# • React.js • D3.js • LATEX
Virtualisation • Angular2+ • Redis
Websockets • VPS/Deployment

German • Spanish

### **OTHER**

Design Related:

Collaboration • Planning • Presenting Retail/Interior and Graphic Design Illustration • CAD • 3D Modelling

# CURRENTLY...

Reading (Fiction):

- Portrait of Dorian Gray Reading (Non-fiction):
- Automate the boring stuff with Python
- •Alex Bellos's Adventures in Numberland

Studying:

- Harvard CS50 Course
- From NAND to Tetris: Building a computer

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **STUDIO XAG** | SENIOR TECHNICAL DESIGNER

September 2016 - Present | London, UK

- StudioXAG produce high-quality creative experiences and spaces for a strong client list
- In my role, I manage junior designers and utilise my experience of problem solving to help facilitate the fabrication process by translating ideas into coherent presentations and drawings for internal and external reference.
- Alongside the daily tasks, I have initiated and developed Internal Web applications using the Django framework which have helped to improve the efficiency of the day-to-day administerial running of the business.

### FORM & BLANK | CREATIVE DIRECTOR

August 2016 - Present | London, UK

• A brand I set up out of a desire to produce handmade, tangible objects alongside my day-to-day virtual creations. I strongly believe tactile craftsmanship often translates into everyday problem solving and provides therapeutic benefits.

## **ELEMENTAL DESIGN** | TECHNICAL DESIGNER

June 2014 - September 2016 | London, UK

# TRO GROUP | GOOGLE SPECIALIST

2012 - 2015 | Bristol and London, UK

• Face to face training retail staff and consumers on the benefits of Web Application Services, Chrome and Android.

# GET TO KNOW ME

### **ABOUT ME**

My legal name is Kyle Perks, although I choose to go by the name Justin Focus. I am a London-based designer and part-time developer.

I'm coming from perhaps an unconventional career/education path with regards to development - though I spend every hour outside of my day job learning to code and understand how things work; and how they could work that little bit better.

Currently, I am looking to move into a development focused career: to push my self-development, fuel my desire to learn and hopefully work on projects that have a great social impact. One thing I enjoy more than working on a project is seeing people using whatever it is I have built.

I love to read, cycle, design and make my own homeware, electronics and clothing. When not doing any of the above, I'm taking my 3 year old Husky, Noah, on adventures around London.

I regularly attend developer meetups and workshops to collaborate and work on open-source projects

Ultimately, I am constantly trying to broaden my thinking and build some awesome things along the way!

### **INTERESTS**

Art and Culture • 3D Design • Drawing • Mathematics/Project Euler Cooking • Electronics Raspberry Pi/Arduino and the IoT • Huskies